Hey guys, welcome to another session.
So in this session we are going to see, we are going to explore the cobalt strike.
So this is one of the powerful C2C framework, which was widely used by the three types as
well as the pentesters.
So I was working in a blue gaming.
When we see the cobalt strike based IPs, cobalt strike based, we will call that as a B cons.
We will literally little bit scared, okay, anyway they are going to be an active threat.
So most of the time, we will have a little fear when we identify the cobalt strike based
IP communicating from any of the process, any of the host units here that are okay.
You need to take care about the kind of things before that was offensive and we are seeing
the offensive and defensive security here.
So we need to understand how the cobalt strike work and how the cobalt strike will operate
and how the threat factors will create the payloads and they will deliver through the
deliver the cobalt strike payload to various methods, okay.
So we will, let us learn about the cobalt strike first.
So don't worry about the cobalt strike and all.
You will get this file in many host resources like virus total or even in Twitter you can
find the cobalt strike file for free, I am not ready to give this cobalt strike to you
because I was downloaded from one of the website, I just sat down to Google and I just
downloaded, okay.
So we are all the cyber security professionals, we are going to.
So we need to crack few things, we need to solve this kind of challenges, okay.
Yup, go ahead and go ahead and search the thing, Google will be easily find out the
cobalt strike, okay.
Once you download the cobalt strike, you can find two things, owners or team servers
and another owner's applying to just click on the team server and go to the directory,
okay, team server directory, let me in a team server directory, the cobalt strike here you
can find all nice, cobalt strike, sorry.
cobalt strike based files, team server, team server, you may general, let's click on the
team server, let's execute the team server, one second, yeah, you need to give the IP of
local machine which you are using, I mean the Kali machine.
So we will start the team server, cobalt strike team servers and here you can see the
team server was running.
The next stage, we need to launch the cobalt strike line, go to the client directory, so
you can see the files here, just launch the cobalt strike, so now you can see there is
one console has been loaded, so you need to give the password which you have given here,
so I have given the password as a password, so it's ready for, so let me giving to connect.
So now you can see the cobalt stick console has been loaded, so here you can find that
there, so we'll explore a few things in the cobalt, so if you go to the help and about here
you can see the cobalt stick version, so 4.7, so probably we'll be getting a little discussion
if you're searching now, so if you go for a new connection or script manager say everything
will be there, but we are using only a few options like payloads, so here you can create
a separate payload like malware and attack a script or web servers and signed applet
attack, a lot of things are there, spearfishing attacks you can do, and before creating
any payloads you need to create a lesion or okay, so just click on the configure lesion
or page, do add, do the name of the cobalt stick decon, we'll do it as a Udemy, let's
give a port, so port will be something like 8, 4, 5, 6, and give a plus symbol, so it will
automatically take the host IP, our calling machine IP, let's save it, so now you can
see the lesion has been started, and here is our lesion or 8, 4, 5, 6 that was a port
or reverse listening port, so we did this thing in a net card NC dash LVP in a previous
videos, but cobalt stick you can easily create a lesion or for that, okay, so next generate
a payload, so windows payload, so click on the lesion or which lesion or you need, choose
the lesion or then click on generate, so now it will ask which directory you need to post,
let me go for our WW, HTML, so over, I will give the name name as anti-virus. This is the
name, which I'm giving, anti-virus.exe, so let's save this, so but anti-virus is like
it's our cobalt stick decon, it's not a real anti-virus, it's a cobalt stick, so this
is the way you need to create a new payload in cobalt stick, you can go for many payloads
like if you need to go for our HTML based payloads, you can even do that, and you can
see the file name called evil.histyay, you can leave that, so let me will save this file,
okay, so save our evil, yeah, evil.histyay, let's see what was inside of the created file,
so here you can find the base 64 encoded payload, so we can try to reverse this payload
in the next video, okay, let's keep for now, and you can, that's your wish, if you need
to create any payloads, you can go and create that, okay, so this is the overall example,
overall, we have a cobalt stick, the console and creating a payload, generating a payload,
so we will decode that payload, which we have created in a dot STF format, and we will
see what's inside that, okay, so let's pop up this video, and we will continue our discussion
next video, see you guys, bye bye.